south side native javon lynn donegan is
forming a well-regulated militia
ladies living in crime ridden chicago
refuse to be victim
the nra loves her because she's
outfitting ladies with glocks
and bedazzled jean jackets now because
all of chicago is a war zone i met javon
in a dark undisclosed location and i
began with a traditional chicago
greeting
are you packing right now
not that i thought you were going to
shoot me ready where is it
i usually carry my firearm on my body a
lady can carry it on the hip
she can carry it on her side in her bra
i think i could tell if there was in the
bralette
nope maybe if you put two of them so
they look even
uh no tell me about the ladies of steel
so the ladies of steel is a gun club
that i founded we now have 120 ladies in
the gun club
ages 25 to about 80. now jovanlin is a
concerned citizen
who feels like she's facing a choice
much like charles bronson
in death wish three the creeps run the
city now
and she's gonna be ready
the reality is violence is everywhere
wherever i am
i'm looking and case in the area to make
sure that i'm safe
is this really the best we can do just
like more guns just giving everyone a
gun
i don't think it's the best we can do
but i don't know if it's any turning
back at this point
but notice javon and her friends are
legally allowed to buy and carry guns
which brings us to the first of three
major myths
the city with the strongest gun laws
in our nation is chicago such
prohibitive gun laws
they have the strictest gun laws in the
country we have
chicago's gun laws become stronger or
weaker in the recent years
well we just um approved concealed carry
five years ago
legal concealed carry plus chicago's
infamous gun ban was eliminated over
eight years ago
after an nra lawsuit chicago used to
have a handgun ban
yes we did have a handgun ban were we
safer then or we say for now
um it seems as though crime spiked after
um
we went to concealed carry now i'm not
sure
of the correlation that's right gun laws
are weaker
and crime went up what are the odds
probably pretty good
but it does explain how chicago became
the perfect punching bag for the right
their gun laws had been wiped away but
the city still had a reputation for gun
control
so it made the lies easier to believe
now chicago myth number two this is a
local
it's all it's all local yeah this is a
local issue
indiana is there right and so what's
stopping people from just buying
firearms and then just driving them into
the
new state well they can
and they do 60 of guns taken off the
streets in chicago
are brought in from other states 20 of
them from mike pence's home state
of indiana and myth number three
chicago is america's murder capital
they have more gun violence than any
other city
what rank do you think chicago is in
homicides i thought
recently we were number one
in fact it's number nine eight other
cities had more homicides
but i think we're number one in
shootings i would not be surprised if
we're not number one in shootings
hmm the shootings number 11.
and by the way st louis sort your
out
now look i know i'm giving javon a hard
time i'm not denying that chicago has
crime
but the point is lots of
loudmouths are drowning out the
actual facts then the more scared people
get
the more guns they buy even though
people on both sides
don't even want them would you prefer it
if you you didn't have to carry again
oh absolutely one day i hope that we can
live like that
would you prefer if you didn't have to
carry a gun uh yes
yes that would be ideal but look on the
bright side
for gun makers chicago is a success
story
and they're not stopping there soon
it'll be easier to buy a gun
soon teachers will have guns a teacher
would have a concealed gun
on them they want to make us all think
living in the wild west where everyone
has a gun is the only way to be
safe so it's up to us to call them on
their
[Music]
you